Where history comes to life.
Night at the Museum is a action, adventure, comedy film directed by Shawn Levy.
Chaos reigns at the natural history museum when night watchman Larry Daley accidentally stirs up an ancient
curse, awakening Attila the Hun, an army of gladiators, a Tyrannosaurus rex and other exhibits.
Larry Daley, played by Ben Stiller.
Rebecca, played by Carla Gugino.
Cecil, played by Dick Van Dyke.
Gus, played by Mickey Rooney.
Reginald, played by Bill Cobbs.
Nick Daley, played by Jake Cherry.
Night at the Museum is a 2006 fantasy comedy film directed by Shawn
Levy and written by Robert Ben Garant and Thomas Lennon.
It is based on the 1993 children's book by Milan Trenc.
The film stars Ben Stiller in the lead role, alongside Carla Gugino, Dick
Van Dyke, Mickey Rooney, Bill Cobbs, and Robin Williams.
It tells the story of a divorced father who applies for a job as a night watchman at New York City's American Museum of Natural
History and subsequently discovers that the exhibits come to life at night, animated by a magical Egyptian artifact.
Night at the Museum premiered in New York City on December 17, 2006, and was
released in the United States on December 22 by 20th Century Fox.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $574.5
million, becoming the fifth highest-grossing film of 2006.
Two live-action sequels were released: Night at the Museum: Battle of the
Smithsonian in 2009, and Night at the Museum: Secret of the Tomb in 2014.
An animated sequel, Night at the Museum: Kahmunrah Rises
Again, was released in 2022 on Disney+.
The film explores themes of night shift, skeleton,
chaos, maya civilization, museum.
The tone is lighthearted.